<resources>
    <string name="app_name">IntentExtrasPractice</string>
    <string name="article_title">NEWS</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">ScrollingText</string>

    <string name="article1">China’s Ambassador to Pakistan, Sun Weidong said on Thursday that the internal changes in Pakistan could not affect Pakistan-China relationship as it was the top priority of Chinese diplomatic policy.

    “I called on the new Prime Minister Shahid Khaqan Abbasi recently and told him that the China-Pakistan relationship is time tested, and China believed that under his leadership, the Pakistani government will be committed to safeguarding national unity and stability and promoting economic and social stability”, he said while addressing a seminar here.

    The Seminar titled “Pakistan-China Relations: CPEC and beyond” was organised by Institute of Policy Studies (IPS).

    Sun Weidong said China Pakistan Economic Corridor (CPEC) had become the most important forum of the bilateral relationship. He informed that construction on CPEC projects was officially started in 2015 and now it had entered into the early harvest stage.

    At the current stage, he said that 19 projects worth over $18 billion were under construction out of which 11 were related to energy sector.

    He said keeping in view the energy crisis in Pakistan, the two countries decided to give priority to energy projects in a bid to give a boost to the economic development of the country.

    The ambassador maintained that the Chinese entrepreneurs have employed over 60,000 Pakistani people under the umbrella of CPEC.

    Moreover, he said the Chinese businessmen had also invested in Gwadar city in fish processing sector, and this move is helping the local fishermen and fisheries related businessmen to improve their lifestyles by earning more after adding value to the sea foods.

    The envoy said that China wanted to see Pakistan a powerful and economically strong country, therefore, it was investing heavily in Pakistan to strengthen the country’s industrial and other sectors.

    He said, “Our cooperation is not against any third country; however, it would be beneficial for the peace and prosperity of the whole region.”

    Senate’s opposition leader Raja Zafarul Haq, who was also chief guest at the seminar, said that the CPEC was not confined to any particular part, and it was owned by the entire nation; therefore work on projects under the umbrella of CPEC would continue irrespective of the internal change in the country.

    He maintained that the bilateral relationship was vital to the global peace and prosperity.</string>

    <string name="article2">Former prime minister Nawaz Sharif began the second day of his rally as he left the Punjab camp house for Lahore today.

After crossing the Katcheri Chowk, Rawalpindi, Rawat and the GT Road towns, the rally has now reached Jhelum.

PML-N leader Amir Muqam while addressing supporters in Jhelum, said that the Khyber Pakhtunkhwa province has been damaged by the PTI and no change has really happened.

“The future of Pakistan is PML-N,” said the PML-N leader.

The former prime minister has reached the dais arranged for his address and is expected to begin his address shortly.

He delivered a short address at Sohawa where while asking his supporters if they have agreed with the Supreme Court decision or not, he said that the people of Pakistan had elected him as the prime minister of Pakistan and the honourable judges sent him home. He also claimed that there are no corruption allegations on him and that he is out to fight for the ‘disqualification’ of the people of Pakistan had entrusted him. He concluded by saying that he is hopeful for the people of Sohawa to support him through thick and thin.

He is expected to address his supporters in Jhelum as well, for which all arrangements have already been done. PML-N’s Talal Chaudhry, however, says that it is up to the party leader to decide where he’d want to address.

On Wednesday, the ousted prime minister and the current chief of the ruling Pakistan Muslim League-Nawaz (PML-N), began his rally from the Punjab House, Islamabad after deciding to go home to Lahore via the GT Road earlier.
He was forced to spend the night in Rawalpindi, however, due to the massive amounts of supporters.

Prior to his departure, Nawaz held a meeting with top party leaders, including Interior Minister Ahsan Iqbal and AJK Prime Minister Raja Farooq Haider.

Former Interior Minister, Chaudhry Nisar did not take part in the rally due to his ‘ongoing back pain,’ as he later mentioned.

The former premier kicked off the second leg of his journey from Rawalpindi’s Kacheri Chowk, where huge amounts of supporters had already gathered.

Special arrangements have been made by the Rawalpindi police to ensure the rally passes through smoothly from Kacheri Chowk, along with the GT Road, to Rawat’s T-Chowk.

Commuters have been warned to use alternative roads once the rally is under way, to avoid unnecessary inconvenience.

The former premier is expected to move through Jhelum, Kharian, Lala Musa and Gujrat to Gujranwala, and then move through Kamoke, Muridke, Kala Shah Kaku, Ferozwala and Shahdara to enter his hometown of Lahore.

According to PML-N leader Zaeem Qadri, the party leaders will decide on the way whether to camp in Jhelum or somewhere else. The distance between Rawalpindi and Jhelum is around 100km and usually takes around an hour or so in normal traffic.

Nawaz Sharif was disqualified as prime minister by the Supreme Court on July 28 in its verdict in the Panama Papers case.

Addressing supporters at Rawalpindi late Wednesday night, he said to his supporters, “Promise me you would get your mandate respected. Promise me you won’t allow your prime minister to be humiliated this way,” he stated.

“If you do not protect your rights, they will continue to be snatched away from you,” he told his supporters.

“The judges said there is no corruption case against Nawaz Sharif, so why was I disqualified? I leave this for history to determined,” noted the three-time premier.</string>
    <string name="article3">KARACHI: Sindh government has issued a notification revoking the applicability of the National Accountability Ordinance (NAO) 1999 in the province.

With NAO revoked the relevant powers are now being accorded to Sindh Accountability Agency.

Sindh Law Minister Zia Lanjar has said that the National Accountability Bureau (NAB) could not take any action against provincial departments anymore.

It may be mentioned here that on July 3 the Pakistan Peoples Party (PPP)-led provincial government in had passed a bill to repeal the applicability of the National Accountability Ordinance (NAO) 1999 to the province.

The National Accountability Ordinance 1999 Repeal Bill 2017 was introduced by the ruling PPP. It aimed to repeal the applicability of the NAO in departments and autonomous bodies controlled by the provincial government.

The bill drew a strong reaction from a well-prepared opposition, resulting in ruckus on the floor of the Sindh Assembly. However, PPP legislators terming the NAB law a ‘black law’ argued that they were acting within their constitutional right to revoke it and give greater powers to the provincial anti-corruption department.

Leader of the Opposition in Sindh Assembly Khawaja Izharul Hassan had opposed the bill saying it was a violation of Articles 248, 143, 8 and 31 of the Constitution.

Critics allege that the new law is aimed at shielding several powerful individuals from proceedings against corruption.</string>
    <string name="news_3">News 3</string>
    <string name="news_2">News 2</string>
    <string name="news_1">News 1</string>
    <string name="todays_news">Todays News</string>
    <string name="news">News</string>
</resources>
